Guide to the Paul Oskar Kristeller Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series I: Correspondence, 1926-1998
  - Subseries I.1: General Correspondence, 1920-1995
    - Polansky-Polk (Box 44)
    - Polka, Brayton 1964-1972 (Box 44)
    - Pollak-Poppi (Box 44)
    - Popkin, Richard, 1951-1993, (2 Folders) (Box 44)
    - Porada-Powling (Box 45)
    - Prague-Preuss (Box 45)
    - Prete, Sesto 1951-1993, (2 Folders) (Box 45)
    - Prezzolini, Giuseppe 1939-1981 (Box 45)
    - Prezzolini-Proskawer (Box 45)
    - Pueyo-Pyott (Box 45)
    - Pulvermann, Marianne 1952-1981 (Box 45)
    - Pyle, Cynthia 1972-1993, (2 Folders) (Box 45)
    - Qingshi-Quondam (Box 45)
    - Rabil, Albert 1977-1990 (Box 45)
    - Radetti, Adelina 1979-1989 (Box 46)
    - Radetti, Giorgio 1939-1976 (Box 46)
    - Rabassa-Ramseier (Box 46)
    - Rand, Various 1939-1981 (Box 46)
    - Randall, Francis 1970-1993 (Box 46)
    - Randall, J.H. 1939-1968 (Box 46)
    - Randall, Mercedes 1940-1972 (Box 46)
    - Randall-Ranum (Box 46)
    - Rao-Rasuuslu (Box 46)
    - Rathe-Razovsky (Box 46)
    - Ray, Gordon 1961-1984 (Box 46)
    - Re-Reeves (Box 46)
    - Regensburger, Reinhold 1936-1972 (Box 46)
    - Reis, Lincoln 1943-1973 (Box 46)
    - Regalado-Rello (Box 46)
    - Reimherr-Reinhold (Box 47)
    - Remak-Rezzani (Box 47)
    - Reynolds, Beatrice 1951-1964 (Box 47)
    - Rice, Eugene 1956-1988 (Box 47)
    - Richards, J.F.C. 1957-1985 (Box 47)
    - Ricci-Rico (Box 47)
    - Riddle-Rigo (Box 47)
    - Risenberg, Peter 1952-1993 (Box 47)
    - Riley, Marjorie 1964-1984 (Box 47)
    - Rilee-Riolanti (Box 47)
    - Riondato, Ezio 1953-1993 (Box 47)
    - Ripin-Ristow (Box 47)
    - Risse, Wilhelm 1957-1972 (Box 47)
    - Ritman-Rizzo (Box 47)
    - Roach-Rockefeller (Box 47)
    - Rodakiewicz, Erla 1942-1961 (Box 47)
    - Roddweig, Marcella 1981-1994, (2 Folders) (Box 47)
    - Roda-Roider (Box 48)
    - Roloff-Roob (Box 48)
    - Rosa-Rose (Box 48)
    - Rose, Hilde and Ernst 1957-1994, (2 Folders) (Box 48)
    - Rose, Paul L. 1969-1994 (Box 48)
    - Rosen-Rosenblatt (Box 48)
    - Rosenberg, Hugo 1928-1940 (Box 48)
    - Rosenberg, J.H. 1939 (Box 48)
    - Rosenberg, Thea 1945-1993 (Box 48)
    - Rosenberg, Werner 1935-1972 (Box 48)
    - Rosenfeld-Rosenwald (Box 48)
    - Rosenthal, Bernard 1954-1991 (Box 49)
    - Rosenthal, Franz 1940-1988 (Box 49)
    - Rosin, A. 1941-1972 (Box 49)
    - Rosmini- Rostovtzeff (Box 49)
    - Ross, Braxton 1965-1988 (Box 49)
    - Rotenstreich-Roti (Box 49)
    - Rotondi, Luisa 1990-1994 (Box 49)
    - Rotondo, Antonio 1966-1994 (Box 49)
    - Rotlin- Ruby (Box 49)
    - Rubinstein, Nicolai 1952-1986 (Box 49)
    - Rucellai- Rudzinski (Box 49)
    - Ruegg, W. 1955-1997 (Box 49)
    - Ruesch-Rutori (Box 49)
    - Ruysschaert, Jose 1961-1984 (Box 49)
    - Ruzicic-Ryskamp (Box 49)
    - Saal-Said (Box 49)
    - Sailor-Salvini (Box 49)
    - Saenger, Frida 1939-1950 (Box 50)
    - Samaritani- Santouosso (Box 50)
    - Sarre, Hans 1933-1991 (Box 50)
    - Saunders, Jason 1949-1974 (Box 50)
    - Sapie-Saxl (Box 50)
    - Scaglione-Schaller (Box 50)
    - Schalk, 1952-1989 (Box 50)
    - Schaller, Dieter 1960-1994 (Box 50)
    - Schaller, Hans Martin 1957-1993 (Box 50)
    - Schaller, Heinrich 1960-1971 (Box 50)
    - Schapiro, Meyer 1943-1976 (Box 50)
    - Schar- Schizerotto (Box 50)
    - Schlass-Schmidt (Box 50)
    - Schmidt, A. and M. 1939-1980 (Box 50)
    - Schmidt, Paul G. 1979-1980 (Box 51)
    - Schmitt, Charles 1957-1986, (2 Folders) (Box 51)
    - Schmitt, Wolfgang 1966-1994 (Box 51)
    - Schmitt,-Schmitz (Box 51)
    - Schnaubelt, Joseph 1973-1993 (Box 51)
    - Schneewind-Schusenberg (Box 51)
    - Schoek, Richard, 1962-1997 (Box 51)
    - Schobinger-Schoyer (Box 51)
    - Scholem, G. 1956-1981 (Box 51)
    - Schrade, Leo 1939-1948 (Box 51)
    - Schrader-Schroder (Box 51)
    - Schubert-Schuyler (Box 51)
    - Schuler, Georgette 1947-1962 (Box 51)
    - Schullian, Dorothy 1953-1983 (Box 51)
    - Schurmann, Reiner 1973-1985 (Box 51)
    - Schulte, H. 1935-1990 (Box 51)
    - Schwab-Scudieri (Box 51)
    - Scuola Normale 1936-1998 (Box 51)
    - Seagraves, Richard 1976-1993 (Box 51)
    - Sebastian, Harry 1955-1985 (Box 52)
    - Searle-Seidermann (Box 52)
    - Secchi-Tarugi, G., 1969-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 52)
    - Seigel, J.E. 1959-1973 (Box 52)
    - Seipler-Seneca (Box 52)
    - Senneff, S. 1975-1988 (Box 52)
    - Senge-Sgnelli (Box 52)
    - Serlupi, G. 1970-1994 (Box 52)
    - Settle, Thomas 1971-1985 (Box 52)
    - Shaaber, M.A. 1955-1970 (Box 52)
    - Schakleford-Shawaker (Box 52)
    - Sheard-Shields (Box 52)
    - Sherman, C. 1974-1986 (Box 52)
    - Shils, Edward 1978-1994 (Box 52)
    - Shinn-Shuster (Box 52)
    - Sicherl, Martin (Box 52)
    - Sibley-Signore (Box 53)
    - Silagi-Simonds (Box 53)
    - Simone, Franco 1951-1967 (Box 53)
    - Simonelli-Simson (Box 53)
    - Simpson, Esther 1934-1982 (Box 53)
    - Sinclair-Sjoberg (Box 53)
    - Sirasi, Nancy 1969-1993 (Box 53)
    - Skeat- Skovortson (Box 53)
    - Slack-Sluder (Box 53)
    - Smaldone-Smith (Box 53)
    - Smith, Leslie 1958-1979 (Box 53)
    - Smith, Morton 1961-1983 (Box 53)
    - Smith, Vincent 1966-1971 (Box 53)
    - Smullyan-Snyder (Box 53)
    - Sobernheim, Rudolf 1943-1994 (Box 53)
    - Solmsen, 1939-1989 (Box 53)
    - Somerville, Bob 1971-1992 (Box 54)
    - Sorabji-Sozzi (Box 54)
    - Soudek, Josef 1951-1994 (Box 54)
    - Spaanjaard, K (Box 54)
    - Spadafora-Speyer (Box 54)
    - Spiedel-Spivakovsky (Box 54)
    - Sporgiano-Squerceate (Box 54)
    - Stablin-Stavrides (Box 54)
    - Stecker-Stegman (Box 54)
    - Stegmuller, 1953-1979 (Box 54)
    - Steinburg, C. 1979-1984 (Box 54)
    - Stein-Steitz (Box 54)
    - Steinitz, Kate 1958-1970 (Box 54)
    - Stella-Stepich (Box 54)
    - Sternburg, Ernst 1936-1976 (Box 54)
    - Stern-Sternfeld (Box 54)
    - Stickler-Stipich (Box 55)
    - Stinger, Charles 1973-1983 (Box 55)
    - Stocchi-Stoya (Box 55)
    - Strach-Strauss (Box 55)
    - Strayer, Joseph 1957-1983 (Box 55)
    - Strittmatter, Anselm 1939-1976 (Box 55)
    - Strevey-Strozier (Box 55)
    - Struge-Stussi (Box 55)
    - Suggs-Suss (Box 55)
    - Suozzi, Michael 1973-1993 (Box 55)
    - Svendson-Swift (Box 55)
    - Sykes-Sypher (Box 55)
    - Szabo-Szybinski (Box 55)
    - Tabarelli-Talbot (Box 55)
    - Taft, Marian 1975-1984 (Box 55)
    - Talmor, Ezra 1980-1994 (Box 55)
    - Tanke-Tate (Box 56)
    - Tateo-Taylor (Box 56)
    - Tecce-Tenfel (Box 56)
    - Tghart-Thirry (Box 56)
    - Thiermann, Peter 1986-1987 (Box 56)
    - Thomas-Thompson (Box 56)
    - Thompson, S.H. 1941-1980 (Box 56)
    - Thorndike-Thumler (Box 56)
    - Tibby-Tissoni (Box 56)
    - Tigerstedt, E.N 1962-1979 (Box 56)
    - Tobias-Tombesi (Box 56)
    - Tonelli, Giorgio 1952-1976 (Box 56)
    - Tonelli, Grazia 1970-1994 (Box 56)
    - Toni, Nando 1967-1969 (Box 56)
    - Toomay-Towner (Box 56)
    - Toscani, Bernard 1965-1993 (Box 57)
    - Traister-Trilling (Box 57)
    - Trinkaus, Charles 1940-1993 (Box 57)
    - Trinkaus (Watts), Pauline 1978-1984 (Box 57)
    - Trimpi-Tseng (Box 57)
    - Tucci-Tynell (Box 57)
    - Tuve, Rosemond 1941-1956 (Box 57)
    - Ueding-Uhlfelder (Box 57)
    - Uhling, Claus 1980-1984 (Box 57)
    - Ulery-Utley (Box 57)
    - Ullman, B.L. 1938-1964 (Box 57)
    - Vacca-Valvo (Box 57)
    - Van Acker-Van Doren (Box 57)
    - Van Dusen, Hugh 1959-1968 (Box 57)
    - Van Egmond-VanZoelen (Box 57)
    - Varaldo-Vazquez (Box 57)
    - Vecce-Venable (Box 58)
    - Velli, Giuseppe and Paola 1955-1984 (Box 58)
    - Venice Committee 1969-1983 (Box 58)
    - Verbke-Vezin (Box 58)
    - Vian-Vidale (Box 58)
    - Viator 1941-1981 (Box 58)
    - Victor, Joe 1967-1978 (Box 58)
    - Vielliard, Jeanne 1948-1965 (Box 58)
    - Vincenti, 1930s (Box 58)
    - Villa-Vitz (Box 58)
    - Visani, L. 1937-1947 (Box 58)
    - Vivarelli, M. 1949-1952 (Box 58)
    - Vlastos-Voltaire (Box 58)
    - Von Bothmer-Vuillemin (Box 58)
    - Waber-Walker (Box 58)
    - Wall-Wallace (Box 58)
    - Wallach, Klaus 1920-1983 (Box 58)
    - Wallach, Luitpold 1956-1982 (Box 58)
    - Wallach-Walsh (Box 58)
    - Walzer, Richard 1936-1973 (Box 58)
    - Walzer, Sofie 1934-1972 (Box 59)
    - Wang-Warfelmann (Box 59)
    - Ward, John 1968-1986 (Box 59)
    - Warkentin, Germaine 1982-1984 (Box 59)
    - Warner-Washington (Box 59)
    - Washburn, R. 1966-1972 (Box 59)
    - Wasow, Wolfgang 1938-1946 (Box 59)
    - Wasserman-Wasznik (Box 59)
    - Watanabe, Mori, 1960-1998, (2 Folders) (Box 59)
    - Watson- Wehmer (Box 59)
    - Weigand, Herman 1934-1993 (Box 59)
    - Weinstock, S. 1932-1962 (Box 59)
    - Weigel-Weisert (Box 59)
    - Weisinger, Herbert 1947-1964 (Box 59)
    - Weiss, Helene 1932-1950 (Box 59)
    - Weiss, Paul 1953-1965 (Box 59)
    - Weiss, Roberto 1950-1969 (Box 59)
    - Weissblum, Alice 1935-1965, (3 Folders) (Box 60)
    - Weissblum, Gunther 1939-1963 (Box 60)
    - Weissman-Weitzmann (Box 60)
    - Welber-Welti (Box 60)
    - Wemple, Suzanne 1959-1993 (Box 60)
    - Wenger, Luke 1983-1998 (Box 60)
    - Wenin, Christian 1968-1982 (Box 60)
    - Wendel-Wertis (Box 60)
    - Werkmeister, W.H. 1956-1972 (Box 60)
    - Wessling-Wetzler (Box 60)
    - Wharton- Whyte (Box 60)
    - White, Lynn 1947-1981 (Box 60)
    - White, Thomas 1974-1990, (2 Folders) (Box 60)
    - Wicher, Helen Brown 1980-1990 (Box 61)
    - Wich-Wietek (Box 61)
    - Wiener, Philip 1938-1986, (4 Folders) (Box 61)
    - Wiervowski, Helene 1946-1994 (Box 61)
    - Wiggins, Henry 1956-1984 (Box 61)
    - Wilbur-Wilkinson (Box 61)
    - Will-Willsea (Box 61)
    - Wilpert-Wilson (Box 61)
    - Wilson, Thomas 1954-1964 (Box 61)
    - Wimsatt-Wissman (Box 61)
    - Winteler 1937-1952 (Box 61)
    - Witt, Ronald 1971-1993 (Box 61)
    - Witkowski-Wolff (Box 62)
    - Wolfgarten-Wonde (Box 62)
    - Wood-Wozniak (Box 62)
    - Wrigley-Wyzanski (Box 62)
    - Wuttke, Dieter 1969-1990 (Box 62)
    - Yates, Frances 1960-1970 (Box 62)
    - Xerox-Young (Box 62)
    - Zaccara-Zayas (Box 62)
    - Zambelli, Paola 1966-1994 (Box 62)
    - Zeddies-Zimmerman (Box 62)
    - Zimmerman, Price 1962-1993 (Box 62)
    - Zinburg-Zygulski (Box 62)
    - Political Letters, 1960-1995 (Box 62)
    - Unidentified Correspondence, 1930-1997 (Box 63)
  - Subseries I.2: Family and Personal Correspondence, 1913-1997
    This subseries includes correspondence with Kristeller's family and personal friends, including letters between Paul and Edith Kristeller and letters between Paul Oskar and his parents and sister.
    - Dated Correspondence, 1913-1997
      - 1917-1923 (Box 64)
      - 1924 (Box 64)
      - 1925 (Box 64)
      - 1926 (Box 64)
      - 1927 (Box 64)
      - 1928-1929 (Box 64)
      - 1939-1940 (Box 64)
      - 1930-1931 (Box 64)
      - 1932 (Box 64)
      - 1933 (Box 65)
      - 1934 (Box 65)
      - 1935 (Box 65)
      - 1936 (Box 65)
      - 1937 (Box 65)
      - 1938 (Box 65)
      - 1913-1939 (Box 65)
      - 1939-1945 (concerning POK's family and their fate in WWII) (Box 65)
      - 1939-1948 (Box 65)
      - 1929-1946 (Box 65)
      - 1945-1951 (Box 66)
      - 1941-1946 (Concerning POK's cousins and their fate in WWII) (Box 66)
      - 1928-1988 (Box 66)
      - 1941-1948 (Box 66)
      - 1939-1950, (4 Folders) (Box 66)
        (Refugee colleagues seeking employment in U.S.)
      - 1988-1997 (Box 66)
    - Alphabetical Correspondence, 1917-1996
      - Belzinger, Louis, 1947-1948 (Box 67)
      - Bertalot, Ludwig (correspondence about) 1951-1983, (7 Folders) (Box 67)
      - Bundesversicherung, 1931-1979, (2 Folders) (Box 67)
      - George and Victoria, 1939-1940 (Box 67)
      - Harke, Marie Anne, 1935- 1975, (10 Folders) (Box 68)
      - Harke, Marie Anne, 1975-1992, (6 Folders) (Box 69)
      - Harke, Marie Louise and John, 1978-1981 (Box 69)
      - Hirsch, Walter, 1941-1944 (Box 70)
      - International Committee for Assistance to Professors, Scholars and Artists, 1945-1948, (2 Folders) (Box 70)
      - Kristeller, Alice and Heinrich, 1917-1932, (7 Folders) (Box 70)
      - Kristeller, Alice and Heinrich, 1932-1941, (10 Folders) (Box 71)
      - Kristeller, Clara, 1926-1934 (Box 72)
      - Kristeller, Edith, 1932-1952, (10 Folders) (Box 72)
      - Kristeller, Edith, 1940-1992, (7 Folders) (Box 73)
      - Kristeller, Paul Oskar
        - To Alice and Heinrich Kristeller, 1938-1939 (Box 73)
        - To Edith Kristeller, 1946-1965, (6 Folders) (Box 73)
      - Krueckman, Oluf, 1946-1947 (Box 74)
      - Lewinnek Family, 1940-1994, (4 Folders) (Box 74)
      - Magnus, Elisabeth, 1935-1953 (Box 74)
      - Magnus, Erich, 1945-1962 (Box 74)
      - Magnus, Gert and Hans, 1932-1987 (Box 74)
      - Magnus, Hans, 1946-1948 (Box 74)
      - Magnus, Margot, 1971-1993 (Box 74)
      - Magnus, Ruth, 1968-1994 (Box 74)
      - Moritz Maria, 1946-1948 (Box 74)
      - Pimm, Lilly, 1947-1957 (Box 74)
      - Pohland, Oskar, 1937-1947 (Box 74)
      - Rosenberg, Herbert, 1945-1983 (Box 74)
      - Ross, Herbert, 1939-1987, (2 Folders) (Box 74)
      - Ross Family, 1980s (Box 75)
      - Sarre, Frau, undated (Box 75)
      - Seidmann, Alfred, 1939-1953, (2 Folders) (Box 75)
      - Shoah Foundation, 1995-1996 (Box 75)
      - Storch, Alfred, 1941-1942 (Box 75)
      - Students from Florence ("Boys in Canada"), 1942-1944 (Box 75)
      - Walton, Marie Louise, 1980s (Box 75)
      - Weissblum, Alice and Gunther, 1939-1956, (2 Folders) (Box 75)
      - Weinstock, Stephen, 1940-1941 (Box 75)
      - Greeting Cards (Box 76)
- Series II: Personal and Biographical Material, 1905-1997
  This series includes personal, biographical, and genealogical material related to both Paul Oskar Kristeller and his wife Edith. There are copies of Kristeller's memoirs "Recollections of My Life" that he wrote and shared with friends and colleagues towards the end of his life, as well as his C.V., Bibliographies, and awards and honors that he received throughout his career. There are also numerous photographs included in this series-- both his family and travel photographs and photographs of Edith Kristeller's family. This series also includes documents related to both Paul and Edith's attempts to collect indemnity pensions from the German Government, their attempts to locate relatives missing after the holocaust, and family trees and genealogical material.
  - Biographical Material
    - Biographical Data, (2 Folders) (Box 77)
    - Student Records, 1905-1926 (Box 77)
    - Birth, Marriage, and Naturalization Certificates (Box 77)
    - Passports (Box 77)
    - Legal Documents, (2 Folders) (Box 77)
      (includes wills)
    - Application Material for German Indemnity Pension, 1957-1975 (Box 77)
      (includes letters of support from scholars including Martin Heidegger)
    - Library Cards (Box 77)
    - Membership Cards (Box 77)
      (For Professional Organizations and Societies)
    - Autograph Book, 1919-1939 (Box 77)
    - Calendars, 1985-1996 (Box 77)
    - Diaries and Notebooks, 1920-1932 (Box 81)
    - Memoirs
      - "Recollections of My Life," 1996, (4 Folders) (Box 77)
        (contains manuscript, drafts, and letters of receipt from friends and colleagues)
      - Autobiographical Note (Box 77)
      - Short, Autobiographical Writings (Box 77)
      - Notes on Kristeller's and Edith's Interest in Music and Literature (Box 77)
    - Oral Histories and Interviews
      - Correspondence-- Paul Oskar Kristeller Oral History Project, 1981 (Box 77)
      - Interview with Marzio Mian in Il Giornale, 1993-1994 (Box 77)
      - Margaret King Interview, 1994-1995 (Box 77)
      - Mesotes Interview, 1991-1992 (Box 77)
    - Obituary Drafts and Instructions, 1997 (Box 77)
    - Curriculum Vitae, (2 Folders) (Box 77)
    - Bibliographies and Lists of Lectures, 1938-1992, (4 Folders) (Box 77)
    - Awards and Honors
      - General, (3 Folders) (Box 77)
      - Talks and Letters Relating to Honors, 1969-1977, 1992 (Box 77)
      - Tributes to Kristeller, (2 Folders) (Box 78)
      - Festschrifts-- Supplementum and Florilegium Columbianum, 1987-1989 (Box 78)
      - "Why Kristeller" lecture -- Introduction to Italian Academy Lecture Series in his honot (Box 78)
      - Honorary Membership in Société International pour L'Étude de la Philosophie Médieval, 1992 (Box 78)
      - John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation Fellowship, 1984-1992, (4 Folders) (Box 78)
      - Kristeller Book Prize-- Renaissance Society of America, 1994 (Box 78)
      - 90th Birthday Celebration/Butler Medal, 1995, (2 Folders) (Box 78)
      - Who's Who in America, 1979-1992, (2 Folders) (Box 78)
      - Plaques, Medals, and Other Award Realia (Box 79)
      - Honorary Degrees (Box 80, 172)
  - Genealogical and Family Material
    - General, (7 Folders) (Box 78)
    - Survivors of the Shoah, 1995 (Box 78)
      (Correspondence and notes related to Kristeller's participation, and a VHS of the final program)
    - Correspondence related to Juden in Kreuzberg and Kristeller Family History (Box 78)
    - Names of Jewish Emigrés from Hamburg (Box 78)
    - Peter Wolff Immigration Material, 1948-1950 (Box 78)
    - Family Trees (Box 78)
    - Printed Material related to or belonging to Kristeller Family (Box 82)
    - Photographs (Box 85)
  - Edith Kristeller Papers
    - Personal (Box 83)
      - Genealogical Material (Box 83)
      - Research and Notes Related to Displaced Family Members (Box 83)
      - Material Related to Emil Luthy (Box 83)
      - German Federal Restitution Claims, 1948-1964, (2 Folders) (Box 83)
      - Address Books (Box 83)
      - Calendar, 1988 (Box 83)
      - Family Photographs, (3 Folders) (Box 83)
    - Professional
      - General, (3 Folders) (Box 83)
      - Curriculum Vitae (Box 83)
      - Medical Notes and Research, 1946 (Box 83)
      - Retirement, 1974 (Box 83)
      - Presentation-- Council for Women in Medicine, 1986 (Box 83)
      - Lecture (Box 83)
      - Publications, (2 Folders) (Box 83)
    - Awards and Honors (Box 84, 173-174)
- Series III: Professional Activities, 1941-1996
  This series consists of Kristeller’s correspondence, research, and writings with various associations, societies, and committees. The records focus on project research for articles and books along with administrative tasks for each organization. The three prominent components of the series are on the Catalogus Translationum et Commentariorum, the Committee to Rescue Italian Art, and the Journal of the History of Ideas.
  - Subseries III.1: General, 1941-1996
    Subseries 1 contains mainly correspondence, with some research and writings, with various committees, societies, and organizations. Prominent records are with the Renaissance Society of America and The State of Learning in the Humanities in Higher Education, also known as the Bennett Committee. Other folders pertain to literary projects, conferences and lectures given on both the west and east coast. The file on the Madrid Leonardo Report are the contents of a dossier assembled by Kristeller, Theodore Beardsley, Jr., and Carlo Pedretti to investigate the circumstances surrounding the rediscovery of a Leonardo manuscript in a library in Madrid.
    - American Association for the Advancement of the Humanities, 1981 (Box 86)
    - American Committee on Renaissance Studies, 1953-1954 (Box 86)
    - ACLS
      - General, 1954-1979 (Box 86)
      - Advisory Committee on Medieval and Renaissance Texts, 1950-1954 (Box 86)
      - Committee on Protection of Cultural Treasures in War Areas, 1944 (Box 86)
      - Committee on Renaissance Studies, 1944-1950 (Box 86)
      - Committee on Renaissance Studies--Notes, undated, 1947 (Box 86)
    - Archivi Danneggiati, 1966 (Box 86)
    - Articella Project, 1975-1995, (2 Folders) (Box 86)
    - Arts Research, 1973-1990 (Box 86)
    - Berkowitz, David Sandler--The Legacy of Humanism, undated (Box 86)
    - Bertalot, Ludwig--Plato Latin Translations, 1980, (2 Folders) (Box 86)
    - Bibliographical Inquiries, 1941-1958, (2 Folders) (Box 86)
    - Blackwell, Constance (Box 86)
    - Brown, Alison Chorley
      - Bartolomeo Scala: Humanistic and Political Writings
        - Manuscript, (5 Folders) (Box 86)
        - Manuscript, (5 Folders) (Box 87)
        - Correspondence, 1982-1992, (2 Folders) (Box 87)
      - "Carmina," 1982-1991 (Box 87)
    - Book Distribution Lists, 1953-1985 (Box 87)
    - Cabeen, David-- Critical Bibliography of French Literature, 1951-1955 (Box 87)
    - Cambridge History of Renaissance Philisophy, 1980-1988, (2 Folders) (Box 87)
    - Center for Medieval and Early Renaissance Studies
      - 1964-1976 (Box 87)
      - 1976-1980 (Box 87)
      - 1980-1985 (Box 87)
    - Center for Research on the Transmission of Classical Texts Through Oriental Languages, 1987 (Box 88)
    - Chiesa, Carlo Alberto, 1993 (Box 88)
    - Clark, Elizabeth-- Notes Taken During Kristeller's History of Philosophy Course, 1963-1964 (Box 88)
    - Columbia University Libraries
      - Correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box 88)
      - Exhibition, 1991-1996 (Box 88)
    - Cornell, William J. and Giles Constable-- "Sacrilege and Redemption in Renaissance Florence: The Case of Antonio Rinaldeschi," 1997 (Box 88)
    - Cusanus Congress, 1959-1964 (Box 88)
    - Dannefeldt, Karl H. (Box 88)
    - Davies, John, 1990-1991 (Box 88)
    - Dictionary on the History of Ideas, 1969-1971 (Box 88)
    - Encyclopedia of Aesthetics Article, 1997 (Box 88)
    - Encyclopedia of the Middle Ages, Renaissance and Reformation, 1976-1981, (2 Folders) (Box 88)
    - Encyclopedia of the Renaissance, 1996-1997 (Box 88)
    - Encyclopedia of Philosophy, 1992 (Box 88)
    - Fellowship Applications and Correspondence, 1947-1949 (Box 88)
    - Ferrari, Lena-- Antonio Ivani, 1984-1994 (Box 88)
    - Folger Shakespeare Library
      - Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 88)
      - Report and Bibliography, 1973-1974 (Box 88)
    - Forte dei Marmi, 1968-1970 (Box 88)
    - Friedrich Frommann Verlag (Günther Holzboog), 1963-1966 (Box 88)
    - Fulbright Fellowship in Italy, 1951-1953 (Box 88)
    - German Higher Education, 1947-1948 (Box 88)
    - Giovannetti, Alberto, 1961 (Box 88)
    - Götte, Christian, 1986-1987 (Box 88)
    - Hankins, James-- "The Baron Thesis After Forty Years," 1994 (Box 88)
    - Hebrew Edition of Kristeller's Works-- Permissions, 1974-1978 (Box 88)
    - Hellenistic Philosophy, (4 Folders) (Box 88)
      (contains manuscripts, publicity material and correspondence with Columbia University Press)
    - Heller, Peter, 1957-1964 (Box 89)
    - Higher Education--Discrimination, Tenure, and Other Issues, 1970-1979, (2 Folders) (Box 89)
    - Historiches Wörterbuch der Philosophie, 1989 (Box 89)
    - International Federation of Renaissance Societies, 1954-1964, (2 Folders) (Box 89)
    - Jaspers, Karl-- Recollections of Karl and Gertrude Jaspers, 1988-1994 (Box 89)
    - Journal of the History of Ideas-- Renaissance Essays from the Journal of the History of Ideas 1989-1993, (2 Folders) (Box 89)
    - Journal of the History of Philosophy--Proposals, 1957-1960 (Box 89)
    - Klustein, Ilana, 1981 (Box 89)
    - Knauer, G.N. (Box 89)
    - Latin Learning--General and Financial, 1956-1966 (Box 89)
    - Latin Manuscript Books
      - Research and Correspondence, 1949-1984, (7 Folders) (Box 89)
      - Indexing, 1983 (Box 89)
      - Manuscript Drafts, 1950-1990 (Box 90)
      - Correspondence, 1987-1995, (4 Folders) (Box 90)
      - Volume II-- Manuscript (Box 90)
    - Lectures and Conferences--Correspondence, 1949-1977 (Box 90)
    - Lectures--Correspondence (West Coast), 1959-1967 (Box 90)
    - Libraries, 1941-1945 (Box 90)
    - Madrid Leonardo Report
      - Contents List for Dossier (Box 90)
      - Documentation, 1959-1993 (Box 90)
      - Newspapers and Magazines, 1967-1993 (Box 90)
      - Scholarly Articles, 1968 (Box 90)
    - Mahoney, Edward (Box 90)